[Music]
Brett Weinstein and Heather hi Inc
became the most high-profile victims of
campus activism when they were chased
out of evergreen college by a student
now it thrust them to national
prominence since then they're finding a
new role as part of what's being called
the intellectual dark web famously you
had the instant evergreen which meant
you had to leave the campus leave you
your post but what's really striking is
that you and Heather were teaching
evolutionary biology so a lot of the
reality of the biological differences
between men and women a lot of these
subjects that are now really hot topics
in the culture within what a lot of
people would recognize as one of the
most progressive left-wing colleges in
the country are there lessons from that
that and also when when you were forced
to leave Evergreen it wasn't the
students that you've been teaching it
was students who hadn't been teaching so
you obviously doing something right in
those in over a decade of being there
what lessons how did he do it what
lessons can we as a culture learn from
that there are tremendous lessons and
the key to what Heather and I were doing
was that we started out by engineering a
community that was safe to have
discussions and discussions that were we
to take what was said in our classroom
and to import it into a faculty meeting
would have caused a conflagration for
sure but you have a group of students
they show up many of them don't even
really know why they're there
Heather and I were doing this for 15
years and a lot of our students came to
us word-of-mouth somebody said oh you
have to take this course and evolution
people who didn't realize they had any
interest in the subject whatsoever would
show up and then you lure them in it's a
question of broadening their worldview
so that they can understand that all of
the things that they
no they care about all of the things
that they find fun to do all of the
pursuits that drive them there their
loves their passions that all of these
things are products of evolution and
that means that understanding evolution
provides a kind of roadmap against the
inner confusion that's a very powerful
incentive for people to embrace it so
the answer to your question is you
provide the safety to explore where
people quickly get the idea that they
are not going to be backed against the
wall for saying something that sounds
radical or off
we had covenants that actually gave
people the right to speak and then
retract what they said if it didn't
sound right or if they changed their
mind or if they came to to see something
about their position they hadn't known
before which meant that they had the
protection of the community just by
virtue of playing in good faith
so the cultivation of what if the term
wasn't so polluted you'd have to call a
safe space is the first the first step
in creating these difficult
conversations and then there's the
incentive to have the conversation which
comes from the fact that you get
something positive for it you know to
understand yourself to understand why
people interact in the way they do is a
very powerful advantage and if you're
presented with the question of would you
like to endure some discomfort in order
to have the power to understand your own
life almost everybody will say yes a lot
of people are describing the
intellectual darkweb as a sort of
placeholder for this is what a
conversation looks like that there's a
lot of different perspectives within it
but what people agree on is this is what
a genuine conversation in good faith
looks like and we've made that a bit of
a focus on our Channel what we've called
the meta conversation what needs to
exist for this meta conversation to take
place and what are the forces are acting
against it the meta conversation
requires a kind of safety
and the thing that the IDW has done is
it has bootstrapped that kind of safety
on topics where people experience in
general a profound lack of safety so I
think the reason that there has been
such a focus on the IDW is that people
through the internet can watch others
saying things the very nuance of which
would cause them to blow up if you said
them you know in a speech on a
university campus let's say and watching
people have those discussions and
respond to each other in spite of
disagreement and not have catastrophe
rein in on them is I think heartening in
fact I know that that's the reaction
because I hear a lot from individuals
who tell me what they see and they are
cheering for the the simple
demonstration that these conversations
are still possible on our channel we've
talked a lot about what we call the meta
conversation and the intellectual
darkweb seems to be an attempt to sort
of carve out a space to be able to have
conversations about things that are very
difficult to have to talk about in the
media and I'm really interested as as
well your background in evergreen
obviously a lot of people know about
what happened and you and Brett being
forced to leave but what really struck
me is that you both were teaching
evolutionary biology there for over a
decade without creating any of these
reactions that we're seeing talking
about the reality of sex differences
talking about these subjects that often
provoked a huge reaction when they're
discussed in the media so I'm really
interested what that was like how you
did it and whether there are any lessons
that we can learn more generally about
how to have these kind of conversations
a technique that both Brett and I used
was to open the first day by saying
don't trust me don't trust me on the
basis of my credentials and my authority
or the fact that certainly that the fact
that I have the power to assess you and
affect your future as a result I have to
earn your trust have to earn your
respect and hopefully over time I will
and you can stop questioning every
single thing that comes out of my mouth
but to begin with please do please do
question that that is actually going to
be a sign of respect
and we both Brett and I insisted on
classrooms that were always respectful
and that always understood that people
disagreeing with ideas was quite
different from proclaiming dislike of
the human beings who were voicing those
ideas and so you know separating out
those two things the human the human the
whole human person and the thing that
they are saying at the moment even if
it's some entrenched firmly held belief
still those are two different things and
disagreement does not this is not the
same as dislike for the person when we
talked together this was particularly
easy to demonstrate because as a married
couple who were presumably not on the
verge of divorce which we which we
weren't we could disagree with each
other and we did and you know even
though we were right in the middle of
our own material you know we were
disagree on topics of sexual selection
and you know evolution of parental care
and you know under what conditions
territoriality involves and these sorts
of things that we were we were always
teaching on and students could observe
how we disagreed what that looked like
and also watch us come back in the next
one and clearly having you know shared
dinner and abend the night before so
this sort of model of intellectual
disagreement disagreement was
particularly easy frankly to do when it
was us together in a classroom and I
think students very quickly did feel
seen and I know that many of them did I
hope that nearly all of them did feel to
some degree understood you know we
insisted on knowing all of their names
very quickly and you know by the end of
the first week of class I would know
everyone's names and at least something
some thing about their developmental
history which would allow me to start
sort of you know building an
architecture in my head
who is this person it's cool still gonna
be a cartoon for quite a while and you
know to some degree we it's all I carry
around with us you know we have these
caricatures that maybe turn to cartoons
that maybe become more fleshed out and
maybe we get these photorealistic images
in our heads of other human beings after
we know them for decades but it's never
complete and so to just start going down
that road to make it clear that you are
going down that road with each one of
the people in the classroom and not
because you think it's your job but
because you're actually very interested
meant that we didn't we were able to
talk about difficult subjects pretty
easily right we and you know in some
ways it was what students were signing
up for you know I didn't the the two
kinds of programs that I did most were
vertebrate evolution which was not did
not fear too much into politically
dangerous territory but animal behavior
is rife with it you know you can't you
can't not go there if you want to do it
honestly and so talking about and you
know and humans are animals so we didn't
we didn't fear from humans and in fact
all the seminars that I tend to do in
those programs were specifically on
humans on human evolution readings what
our history has looked like and mostly
our prehistory and frankly students
especially from historically
marginalized and oppressed groups were
particularly interested several several
people told me nearly every year I
taught this material but they were
particularly interested to finally get a
read on what it was that evolution had
to say about about being gay or about
different races or about especially in
you know in my case I would teach a lot
on sex and gender and you know on on
what it was to be male versus female and
also to specifically be educated and how
to assess bad logic because that that
was the thing you know that's anyone
who's teaching in 2018 or the 21st
century in general and is teaching a
litany of fact is not doing their
students a service you can get that on
Coursera or Wikipedia or any
mooks you know it's just it's it's all
about one line all the facts are there
to be found what you want to in the
classroom is develop relationship so
that you can call people out when they
say things that contain by the pneuma
logical fallacy or don't allow you to
you know you if it's unfalsifiable if
you proclaim something that's
unfalsifiable you can watch as you know
I the faculty or somewhere there's two
initiative caught up go well I actually
cannot respond to that here's why that
means that what you've just proposed me
is not a testable hypothesis this we
can't do science on it and if you want
to take some other way of knowing and
try to try to do it with what you've
said okay
but if we are trying to figure out what
is true science is the best tool we've
got and we can't do science on the thing
you've said what can we do to what
you've said to make it falsifiable and
then let's work as hard as we can to
falsify it and then if we can't the
longer we can't the more likely it is
that it is true even though we'll never
completely know that and why is that
freeing it's so freeing it's an it's
actually educational and students walk
out going okay I am now freed to think
for myself whereas I felt sort of roped
in by Authority and I think most
educators most people who are in
educational roles do a better job of
demonstrating their own authority than
they do have actually freeing students
from the yoke of that authority of
learning to think for themselves and
what do you think of the principles for
discussing these kind of topics that you
could take from your experience at
Evergreen and take out into the world
certainly having some sort of a document
in advance that everyone has agreed to
is incredibly useful
you also need someone who's willing to
and enabled to enforce it and in the
modern authoritarian left landscape
enforcers are always seen as bad you
know hierarchy is it's a sign of
patriarchy and all of this but you you
actually can't just have something like
the Chicago principles or what was
called a covenant in an evergreen
classroom which established in advance
what the responsibilities are between
all the players between
students in both directions and what do
you do if you have a conflict and you
know all of all of the things that you
should expect in an honorable community
and in the case of a classroom as much
as you know it was it was easy to handle
the authority it on an everyday basis
and say please question anything that I
say that you don't agree with but the
fact is it wasn't a complete handing
authority because I was still faculty at
the end of the day and so it was still
clearly my you know I was still going to
be the arbiter of of disputes that came
up so you need that how do you scale
that into a non classroom situation
where there is no clear even an
authority that wants to cede their
authority you need someone who can step
in and say mmm you're you're going
against the rules and you mentioned the
Covenant before that is that really
important to basically ask people to buy
into a set of principles before engaging
in the conversation covenants were a
feature of Evergreen from its founding
so the founders of the college decided
that every class should begin with a
covenant between professor and student
in which the expectations were set out
most of the covenants that I saw were
uninteresting but it was a place where
if you chose to you could do a lot of
work and the key utility is that by
setting the expectations out as you come
through the door while you still have
the right to say huh maybe this program
isn't for me that means that later on
when you invoke this covenant and say
well you agreed to this set of rules why
are you now saying something else people
people recognize that that the
obligations they've signed up for are
important and I will say one of the
things that I started adding to my
covenants late in my teaching at
Evergreen was that this is not an end
user License Agreement and user license
agreements are designed so you won't
read them so you won't understand what
your rights and obligations are the
Covenant was the opposite of
it was imperative that you read it so
that you understood why you were being
expected to do X Y & Z along the way and
by and large it worked quite well we
spent time on these things on the first
day of class of people so people got it
and then having signed up for it in my
experience and Heather's experience
people pretty well lived by it and we
had communities of good faith
interactants that functioned beautifully
most of the time and how do we take
those lessons out and apply those in the
world more generally I mean the
intellectual dark web is one attempt at
creating this kind of safe space want of
a better word but are there are other
ways that we can do it well the problem
is you will immediately not having such
a covenant you will immediately trip
over the following problem if you
attempt it the Covenant is exclusionary
what you are really saying when you set
out an agreement about how we will talk
and disagree and challenge each other is
you are saying that if you don't agree
to these rules you're not welcome here
now nobody likes to hear you're not
welcome here and at the moment that sets
people off it's I have a hair-trigger
for being told somebody's not welcome
there who are you to say who's welcome
and appoint as well no I'm not telling
you you're not welcome I'm telling you
anyone who doesn't agree to this set of
good faith principles isn't welcome and
as soon as you do agree then you are so
you're the one deciding whether you're
welcome or not having decided to live by
these rules then you get the benefits of
what is in effect a much more capable
but more fragile conversation and this
is I think one of the hardest lessons of
well the hardest lessons for me at least
of complex systems is that very often
the most capable creatures or mechanisms
are also the ones with the narrowest
requirements so that a beautifully
architected creature may have very
precise limits on what it can tolerate
the beautiful conversation that is
capable of traversing some new landscape
and doing
deftly that conversation does not happen
when anybody can law any accusation at
any moment with no evidence it happens
when people are protected enough to try
out difficult things and then to adjust
their position and learn where they've
arrived so the upshot you have to be
able to exclude in order to do the
extraordinary doesn't mean that you're
excluding people for arbitrary reasons
you're excluding them for very simple
reasons which is that their presence
will destroy the attempt so I think we
have to figure out how to intelligently
exclude in the interest of accomplishing
something for which there is obviously a
great hunger and that great hunger
implies that there is a deficit and if
you were to distill down what say three
or four principles of having a
generative conversation in good faith
are what would they be what conditions
allow for that so how do you know you're
having one maybe like what are what are
the what are the signals that you're
actually doing it right but you're
actually having a good conversation no
wrote apologies apologies for actual
wrongs but no wrote apologies do not
apologize for things that you did not
actually do and if you see sort of a
culture of rote apology in a big
conversation
there's probably fear right underneath
the surface similarly I would say look
for laughter look for humor look look
for and not just you know there's
everyone can tell the difference between
a nervous laughter and and regular from
the gut laughter in which things even
when you didn't see something coming or
maybe that's often when things get funny
when a conversation that was very
serious or very technical suddenly
erupts and laughter if that can happen
there's probably not fear right beneath
the surface and and obviously laughter
is also a way that people people bond if
you know this doesn't happen in every
conversation that is that is
far-reaching and good faith but
obviously if you see people changing
their minds or people challenging one
another and coming away with any
evidence of change perspective that's
that's sort of just too obvious I guess
I guess those first two that I came up
with or maybe maybe two that I remember
most fondly from the collapse from both
you know these three-hour meandering
interactive lectures or labs or even
more often you know long meals on field
trips where students cooked and then we
all ate together and then we might sit
around the table for hours afterwards
ago and sit around a campfire and having
such conversations that ranged from
deeply theoretical science to the state
of the world to individual stories from
people's childhoods about their siblings
or their animals or the adventures
they've been on interspersed with I mean
this is always helpful to someone breaks
out a guitar and you know just just like
laughing together singing together is a
way to bring people together so these
are some of the things that can't happen
online
which is part of I think why we find
such an impoverished and quick to anger
set of conversations online that we're
missing they're just like the actual
visceral being in each other's presence
and that very quickly allows us to let
our guard down you you mentioned this
sort of sense of fear under the surface
which I think a lot of people would say
it's very present at the moment in a lot
of conversations did you feel that fear
in Evergreen until things erupted it
that's an interesting question yes
because Brett and I are married and
we're faculty there together and we're
watching the whole thing unfold we
didn't feel fear we like we weren't
afraid but there was a definite culture
of
fear in which people were not speaking
what they knew to be true and Brett
heard this much more than I did because
he was more public with his
disagreements with what the
administration was doing but after every
time that he would stand up in a faculty
meeting or send an email to the faculty
and staff email list he would have
several sometimes very many faculty and
staff come to him privately on private
channels either in person or over email
and say thank you I can't say it because
that's a culture of fear and in fact he
claimed this he said this six months or
so before the Evergreen protests became
public and went viral and the response
he said this I think over email and the
response from some of the faculty who
were leading the charge who are leading
the authoritarian leftist charge was
there's no culture of fear prove it who
has come to you well I'm not going to
tell you who has come to me because
that's exactly how this this would work
and you know people will continue to
come to me only you know only if I
protect them and you know I think one
thing that I won't speak for Brett here
but one thing that I think I wish that I
had done differently was ask people who
were coming to us privately to speak up
I did on a couple of occasions and there
are a lot of reasons not to and I
understand them but this could have had
a totally different ending and
furthermore it could have modeled for
everyplace else that this is happening
which is to say just about every
American campus a lot of workplaces and
boy have we heard stories you know we
the the college campus ones are easy to
report on because they tend to be in
these public places with you know poor
young indoctrinated students apparently
making asses of themselves but it's
that's not the real story you know it's
I really don't think that there they are
the ones who are driving this and what
we have you think it's the professor's
driving it yeah yeah it's it's the
professor's it's the professor's and
increasingly the administrators and
that's not to say that students don't
have agency but very little of these
modern protests looks like protests the
likes of which I remember I participated
in it feels very much more about
orthodoxy and about falling into line
and about reading from a script' and the
fact that I have now seen not just at
Evergreen but at two different
conferences and a couple of other places
as well
these attempted power grabs in some
places successful like at Evergreen in
some places not in which the the
authoritarian power grabbers start using
all the same words it's it's all on the
same script so it's it's not that there
is some central clearinghouse where it's
coming out of but but it comes from some
traditions within unfortunately within
the humanities increasingly being taught
at schools of Education and therefore
spreading very quickly into the k-12
system primary and secondary school and
thus frankly indoctrinate and whole
hosts of children who are now coming of
age and don't have the tools with which
to question what it is they're being
told so I would say increasingly it will
become a problem that the young people
themselves are perpetrating on the world
but at least until very recently it was
being driven by the faculty it was
driven being driven by the people who
were supposedly the adults who were
supposed to know better and who didn't
and that's why I would say I wish that I
had had the foresight to ask anyone who
came to Brett Army privately and you
know maybe not to push it but to ask
will you please say this publicly and
for the most part I didn't for the most
part I said thank you it's good to know
we're out alone and that's true it's
it's very good to know you're not alone
when you're facing some you're really
stupid and horrifying stuff but it's not
enough
ultimately what you need is actually not
that higher percentage of people to
stand up and say I see this and the
emperor has no clothes you know like
that that's that's what it is you're
waiting for that moment and one or two
or three people isn't enough yeah a
group that that's that is that big when
the when the authoritarians on the left
are shrieking in language that sounds
sort of very superficially like it's
anti-racist and anti-sexist and anti
homophobic alavesa that's what they say
they're doing and some of them in the
movement actually I think really do 100%
believe that that's what they're doing
but in effect they're having exactly the
opposite they are having exactly the
opposite effect what do you think those
the minimum rules are that you would
have to sign up to to to have a
generative conversation well I know
something about what the rules are
having played around with different
covenants with different classes at
Evergreen but I would also say the most
interesting thing about the IDW
phenomenon is that we don't have a
written set of rules what happened is
people who separately had arrived at
some sort of kit for doing this kind of
work found each other because the world
had become a place in which conversation
had become impossible so if conversation
is impossible because saying things that
should be say about causes a blowout and
then you run into people where you can
say those things and no blowout occurs
it's natural for you to gravitate so the
most fascinating thing to me is that
this brought people from so far afield
from such different backgrounds of such
different political perspective and
effectively what unites that to the
extent of the IDW is a group what unites
that group is the discovery of the
toolkit for participating in incredibly
difficult discussions and if you were to
name those principles what
well once you have established that your
community in which you're having a
discussion is a good faith community in
which essentially every person has
agreed with the idea that they would
rather lose if they have an incorrect
argument than win in other words if your
priority is getting to what is true and
that priority supersedes your own rise
then you can do a great deal and what
happens at that limit is you can assume
that the other people in the
conversation are making a kind of sense
and to the extent that they sound like
they are not making a kind of sense you
know where to look you do not resort to
the accusation you are being absurd you
say I wonder why it is that when I hear
through my ears what you have just said
does not add up in the slightest so let
me try out what I hear you saying and
you tell me where I don't have it so
that's the steel Manning aspect which is
really a a formalization that has caught
on of some instinctive process where in
order to reach some new place with
somebody you have to understand what
they're saying not just enough to
counter it but you have to understand it
well enough to know what really might
actually be wrong with it which means
you have to also know what's right with
it so it is the I mean I think
overarching lis it is the question of
what role argument plays if argument is
a tool to accomplish political ends you
can't have these conversations if
argument is a tool to discover what's
true from which might flow a political
desire but it is not the motivating
force then you will act very differently
as you argue you will argue from a
perspective of good faith and you
if you're in a position to expect good
faith from whoever you're arguing with
you have the potential of both arriving
at some place better than you start it
out you might both learn and that's you
know it's win-win and now the image of
Evergreen is very poor after what's
happened what but I know that you've
spoken before about that there was a lot
of really good stuff going on there a
lot of really inspiring stuff what are
the other things that you would like to
see as the positive aspect of evergreens
teaching style that you think we can all
learn from well I've thought a lot about
this because it seems to me that
evergreens model was half brilliant and
half crazy and there was no reason that
you couldn't take the crazy part and
eliminate it and have improved the model
but there was something about treating
the founding structure as sacred that
prevented the population of evergreen
from repairing itself which resulted in
the blowing up the key factors that
worked were an unparalleled level of
pedagogical freedom so professors really
had carte blanche to teach what they
wanted how they wanted and that meant
that people who wish to discover what
was possible could could explore and
that was coupled with a that was coupled
with a classroom structure in which
students took one class full-time and
professors taught one class full-time
and those classes could go on for two or
three quarters in some cases what that
meant was that you had a tremendous
amount of high quality contact with your
students so if you were dedicated to the
job of teaching in some new way you knew
exactly who you were teaching just at
the level of every individual in the
room was known to you that meant you
could track the blind spot that a
student had and you could work you could
tailor what you were saying and you
could try to make sure that it landed on
a particular mind in a particular
way that would cause some epiphany that
needed to happen I don't know of another
model in which that's possible that
requires the freedom and the high
intensity of contact between professors
and students and if I was architecting a
college in the aftermath of the
experience of teaching at Evergreen I
would preserve those things above all
others what I would do away with is the
mechanism for hiring professors and
recruiting students both of those
mechanisms were badly broken and they
meant that the population that arrived
at Evergreen was not the right
population to take advantage of those
structures it was a haphazard mix so the
main problem with hiring was that it was
done by grouping faculty together and
asking them what positions we thought we
should hire rather than looking at whose
classes were full and saying well if
psychology is always full we need some
more psychology professors now I'm not
an absolutist in this regard I wouldn't
say that whatever the population coming
to the college wants we should hire as
many people as as it can handle but I do
think within limits you need a feedback
mechanism that tells you what is
succeeding which classes are resulting
in students walking away feeling like
whoa that was definitely worth my time
and my tuition money rather than walking
away saying what the hell was that and
why did I spend 10 weeks on it so had
there been a feedback mechanism that
caused that which worked to be
propagated evergreen would have been a
much more effective place evergreen also
had an almost complete disconnect
between the admissions office and the
recruiters and the faculty so we often
as faculty had no idea how the college
was being advertised and to whom and
really Evergreen was largely advertised
as a pretty liberal arts college on the
Puget Sound when that was the last
reason you should go there it was really
the place to go if you
had very high potential but you needed
somebody to treat you as an individual
because you weren't perhaps well built
for school or you were capable of
something extraordinary that was going
to require somebody to pay particular
attention to your your skills those were
reasons to go but they weren't anywhere
in the recruiting materials so what we
got was a haphazard collection of
students Heather and I did very well in
this environment because our programs
were always oversubscribed and so in a
sense although only rarely we'll be in a
position to have an application for a
program that would allow us to choose
the best students for it we were in a
position to discourage people who would
not benefit from our programs and
encourage people who would benefit and
when you get a room full of people that
are more or less there because either
they think they need to hear what you're
saying or you think they might benefit
from it there's a tremendous amount of
potential and Evergreen now has a pretty
toxic reputation and it's better to say
and but what are the what are the good
parts of the Evergreen model that you
think we can learn from we should learn
from we had time we had academic freedom
and with those two things and good faith
and you know like I said a classroom
effectively has either a benevolent or
an envelope monovalent dictator there is
an authority figure no matter how much
of the authority they want to turn away
so in in my case I think I was always a
benevolent dictator basically enforcing
rules of decency such that we had we'd
never prioritized justice over truth but
we got both because we did so because we
investigated what was true with a sense
of of care and compassion and most
colleges and universities just don't
afford the time so study abroad trips
where students will go for a month or
two could but for the most part those
are these one-off things where the
students aren't even from the same
University
till they show up somewhere far-flung
and then they're mostly you know if
they're in city is they're in someone's
dorms and it's it's it just doesn't
really create community the same way so
really being able to dive deep with
people and reveal truths about yourself
not just what you think and how you
think but also just about who you are as
a person such that everyone in the
community is a little bit exposed and
once everyone's a little bit exposed and
you can see okay we have all trusted
each other a little bit here and we are
all therefore assuming that there is
safety in that I can afford to take
intellectual risks and I'm not going to
be attacked for doing so and that's
that's we were able to do year after
year after year so breath said it before
but you know I was on sabbatical when
the protest happened at Evergreen and
not a single one of the students who
showed up to protest against him did
here I know you know this this wasn't
our students who turned against us that
didn't happen
if that had happened that would be a
totally different story and you know I
would I would hope that you would be
pushing back on my story of you know how
effective this was right I give if we
have legions of students or any even you
know a couple you know find out what
their story is find out actually what it
is that they're saying that disagrees
with what wouldn't Bretton on my claim
about what we were doing for 15 years on
campus was and I'm sure I know for sure
that given that the college that we
loved hired a PR firm to basically
demonize Brett and then us that they if
they could have found such students they
would have and we'd be hearing from them
but they they haven't so the fact the
fact is that people become loyal when
they are treated well and if you're only
treating people well in order to create
loyalty that's not actually being
treated well and smart young people can
see that and so actually action and
smart everyone can see that but I think
you're even more able to see that one
year when you're young and fresh
you've just been no matter how good your
school experience was you everyone has
had some just awful teachers who clearly
disrespected them as individuals didn't
really believe in their humanity didn't
really think much of them kind of just
hoping to be done with it so they could
you know would tire whenever they're
retiring or don't drink that night or
whatever it was and at the point that
students show up in a classroom and the
faculty says I know you've had awful
educational experiences even if even if
you're an awesome student and you've had
mostly excellent educational experiences
I know that you've probably been been
taught with a combination of fear and
authority and pointless work and I hope
to do none of those things and I
encourage you to call me out if you
think that's what I'm doing that was
possible that was possible with time in
a way it's not you know we meet for an
hour twice a week kind of class
[Music]